# Raymond Wu

raymond.wu@carleton.ca n raymondwu1.github.io linkedin.com/in/rwu1

#### **SUMMARY**

Upcoming software engineering graduate with a passion for programming and ability to learn new technologies in a fast-paced environment. Expert in agile methodologies and industry experience in all aspects of software development including building, testing, integration and deployment. Self-motivated and proven to effectively collaborate with diverse teams to push new features and automate workflow. Proficient with Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS and databases like MySQL and MongoDB.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Developer Intern**

Sept 2016 – Jan 2017

Quest/Dell Software Group | Kanata, Ontario

- Developed application modules for a SaaS product in an agile/scrum environment using C# with Visual Studio, Jenkins, git and JIRA.
- Participated in active code reviews, and created end-to-end acceptance tests using Cucumber
- Created the Jenkins pipeline script and pushed updates to automate the integration, testing and deployment of the source code based on feedback from the development teams
- Developed PowerShell scripts to automate deployment of various components to the cloud hosted on Microsoft Azure and AWS
- Collaborated with the front-end team to automate the setup of their software environments

### **Junior Software Engineer**

Jan 2016 - April 2016

Communications Research Centre | Nepean, Ontario

- Developed software for integrating systems and basic data analysis applications for cloud processing using WinForms in C# and the Smart Things API in Groovy
- Implemented network analyzing software to analyze data transfer and power levels between devices in an 802.11n network
- Optimized networks by over 30% by monitoring data traffic and adjusting appropriate devices
- Built an IoT testbed to analyze the interference between multiple devices using various wireless protocols like Wi-Fi, Zigbee, Z-Wave and Bluetooth

### **APPLIED PROJECTS**

- Developed and tested a file sharing simulator in Java using Junit as a testing framework
- Worked in a team to develop, test and deploy a perk manager web application using Spring MVC, REST, PostgreSQL, GitHub and Heroku to achieve continuous integration and delivery
- Worked in a team to develop a file transfer system in Java that allowed concurrent clients to connect and read/write files to a server using the TFTP protocol on top of UDP

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

- Developed games like breakout, snake and tetris using HTML5 canvas, CSS and JavaScript
- Built a hi-fi music center using the Raspberry Pi through SW/HW implementations on Linux
- Developed a GUI application in Java to search for music sheets stored in a database using SQLite
- Developed a calculator web application using React

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Java, C/C++, C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, REST, jQuery, Hibernate, Spring, TCP/IP, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, git, Slack, GitHub, Bitbucket, Bamboo, Jenkins, Agile

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering | Carleton University, Canada | Sep 2013 – Nov 2018 Honors: Lester Bowles Pearson Entrance Scholarship, Dean's Honour List 2013-2014 Full Stack Web Development Certification | 1800 Hour Program | FreeCodeCamp | In progress Relevant Coursework: Responsive Web Design, JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, Front-End Libraries, Data Visualization, APIs and Microservices, Information Security and Quality Assurance